# RODRIGO MAIA FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, BR

EMAIL • rodrigo.maia.pereira@gmail.com PHONE • +55 (31) 994175953 WEBSITE • http://rodrigomaia.me

#### **PROFILES**

linkedIn github

# **ABOUT**

Full-stack developer with a profound interest in creating/implementing great user interfaces. I have greater proficiency in Javascript and Typescript (Node/React), although I have already contributed to projects with total or partial focus on Ruby, Python and Java.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Software Engineer, Trusted Health Inc

January 2022 - Present

Member of the team responsible to mantain external and internal apps related to financial services.

# Frontend Engineer, Fauna Inc.

**January 2020 - January 2022** 

Member of the team responsible to mantain and implement new features on multiple apps directly used daily by our customers. Using typescript in most projects, also implemented new features on Rails services

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

- Ran the migration of our biggest project from Javascript to Typescript
- Implemented a one-click-deploy strategy using github actions and a custom made Slack bot (also written in typescript)
- Pushed for inovation on react apps
- Implemented serverless functions using typescript.

# Senior Software Engineer, Decisiv Inc.

September 2018 - January 2020

Working in a fully remote team aimed to develop new features and improvements to the main company product. Mainly focused on services written with Ruby on Rails and Elixir/Phoenix, also maintaining/creating user interactions with Angular.

### Consultant Developer, ThoughtWorks Brazil

November 2014 - September 2018

ThoughtWorks is a consultancy focusing on software delivery, technical excellence and social and economic justice. I Worked in many projects involving agile methodologies and intense client collaboration. Always involved with several technologies and high-quality delivery. I had opportunities to works with local and remote clients exploring the best practices to ensure the best result. Currently assigned as a product engineer to build a staffing solution for internal use across all of Thoughtworks' offices, focusing on building a high quality product, with technologies such as Ruby on Rails and ReactJS, and experimenting with new approaches to agile methodologies.

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

- Developed several cloud-first applications using tools docker and kubernetes
- For a big flight company built critical systems to provide data synchronization at real-time.
- Developed self-provisioning (using Ansible) applications and implanted Continuous Integration with parallel pipelines.
- Wrote test-first node.js web applications accordingly with the test pyramid methodology.
- Presented workshops about React and ES6

## Developer, Ezlike

November 2013 - November 2014

I was responsible to maintain and integrate new features to the main product of the company. In a few months we were able to implant TDD, continuous integration, GIT source control and asynchronous programming. We are always concerned for the scalability and usability of the application. I less than a year, we have implemented a new architecture that was able to triple its capacity to attend customers.

# Developer and Systems Analyst, webAula S/A

June 2013 - October 2013

I was a developer working on the company's innovation team and I was responsible for analyzing and implementing new features and technologies on its product at the time. I was also responsible for promoting the use of agile methodology within my team and I have implemented TDD on the company's development process.

# Developer and Systems Analyst, Arkhi Consultoria e Treinamento

January 2011 - May 2013

I did work related to software engineering applied to products development and IT consultancy, such as requirements, analysis, programming, tests, implantation, configuration management and support.

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

- I have developed BRMS applications using the Jboss Drools Expert platform, having participated of the implementation of the rules engine and on the creation and use of simple business rules. The project had its response time on the alteration and composition of the commissioning structure reduced, ensuring greater flexibility and agility.
- I have worked on the development of projects that used software integration solutions recognized by the market, such as WebServices, as well as widespread Java and .NET patterns and frameworks.
- I have been trained on the architectural software principles with focus on the definition and on the identification of requirements and architectural conductors, as well as the usage of the architectural conductors for building the proof of concepts and the applications structural architecture.

# **SKILLS**

# **Development**



# **EDUCATION**

Technician, Industrial computer science - Centro Federal de Educação tecnológica de Minas Gerais
January 2008 - December 2010